[Music]
[音乐] 大家
hi everyone Harry Frank here from red
好，我是来自 Red Giant 的 Harry Frank。
giant in this tutorial we're going to be
在本教程中，我们将
talking about motion paths in trapcode
讨论 Trapcode 中的运动路径。
particular this is a curious little
这是 Trapcode
feature found in the physics section in
物理引擎中一个非常独特的小功能，
trapcode particular and the way it works
它的工作方式
is fairly unique but it has a lot of
相当独特，但
applications especially if you need to
用途广泛，尤其是在需要
guide your particles along a very
引导粒子沿着
specific path and this works really well
特定路径运动时。
if you're trying to integrate movement
如果您尝试
within 3d even if you need particles to
在 3D 中集成运动效果，或者需要粒子
go behind things and you're perhaps
穿过物体后方，即使您正在
working in cinema 4d and we'll go
使用 Cinema 4D，这个功能也非常有效。我们将
through some examples of this using
使用
cinema 4d Lite and creating some
Cinema 4D Lite 来演示一些
particle swirls around objects but let's
围绕物体旋转的粒子效果。但
start with the simple part of what a
首先，让我们了解一下什么
motion path is and how this differs from
是运动路径，以及它与
might use in After Effects so I'm gonna
After Effects 中使用的标准光源有何不同。我将使用
steal this little blue background to
一些蓝色背景来
make things look a little more
让画面看起来更
interesting and let's create a solid I'm
有趣，然后创建一个纯色背景。我将
gonna use the quick key to apply my last
使用快捷键应用我之前的
effect
效果——应用“特定”效果。
I'm just apply particular now in other
在之前的
tutorials we've learned about using
教程中，我们已经学习了如何使用
lights as emitters with in particular in
光源作为“特定”效果的发射器。
fact this is a very useful feature if I
事实上，这是一个非常有用的功能。 我创建了
create a light and I name it emitter I
一个光源，并将其命名为“发射器”。我
can use this lights 3d position to
可以利用这个光源的3D位置来
dictate where my particles are generated
控制粒子的生成位置。
so I'll go to my emitter type and set
所以我将发射器类型设置
this to lights and if I animate this
为“光源”。如果我播放动画，
we'll see that the space in which
我们会看到
particles are generated will follow the
粒子生成的空间会跟随光源移动。
however motion paths are very different
然而，运动路径与
from this in this case we're defining
此截然不同。在这种情况下，我们定义的是
the emitter position so this is where
发射器的位置。
the particles are continuously generated
粒子会在这里持续生成，
as they are created they continue to
它们会不断
move outwards but the light emitter
向外移动，但光源
itself doesn't affect the path of the
本身并不影响粒子的路径。
particles the particles are not flowing
粒子不会
along this path the area in which the
沿着这条路径流动，
particles are born is just being
粒子的生成区域只是
dictated from the 3d position of the
由光源的3D位置决定的。
light so not to be confused with light
所以不要将运动路径与光源混淆，它们
emitters motion paths are a very very
是完全
different thing
不同的概念。
so I'm going to take this light and
因此，我将重命名这个光源，并将
rename it and I'm gonna call this motion
其命名为“运动
path one and I'll make a path that's
路径1”。我将创建一个
slightly interesting here
略微有趣的路径。
so now in particular I'm going to close
现在，我将
out the intersection and we are actually
关闭交叉点。实际上，在
well first before I close that out I
关闭交叉点之前，我
need to set this to something that is
需要将其设置为非
not lights that's very important we're
光源类型，这一点非常重要。我们
not using a light emitter we're using
不会使用光源。 我们使用
the spline of the motion path to define
运动路径的样条曲线来定义
the flow of the particles but how they
粒子的运动轨迹，但粒子的
emit is still defined in the emitter
发射方式仍然在发射器
section and we do not set this to lights
部分定义，而且我们没有将其设置为灯光，
so I'm going to set this to point four
所以我现在将其设置为点 4，
now and maybe we can change this up a
也许我们可以稍微调整一下，
little bit but point is just fine so
但点 4 已经足够好了。接下来，
I'll go to the physics section under
我将转到物理部分，在
error and select motion path one you'll
误差下选择运动路径 1。你会
notice that we've got lots of room for
注意到我们有很多空间可以添加
additional motion paths with additional
其他运动路径，并进行其他
uses of particular but I'm going to just
特定用途，但我只
use this one right here the difference
使用这里的这个。1
between the 1 through 9 and the HQ
到 9 版本与 HQ
versions is that the HQ versions are
版本的区别在于，HQ 版本速度
slightly slower but do a more detailed
稍慢，但对运动路径进行了更精细的子
subsampling of the motion path but
采样。
generally you'll find that the standard
通常情况下，你会发现标准
motion path will work just fine so
运动路径就足够了。
you'll notice immediately that my
你会立即注意到我的
particles are taking on a flow that
粒子正在沿着模拟
mimics the overall path of my light
光源整体路径的运动轨迹运动。
now it still has its default velocity of
现在它们仍然保持默认速度
100 so they're flowing along this path
100，所以它们沿着这条路径运动，
but they still have a bit of velocity
但它们仍然有一定的速度。
I'm just going to turn this down like I
我只需要像我提到的那样降低这个速度。
mentioned the speed at which they flow
它们
along the path is dictated by how fast
沿着路径运动的速度是
this path draws on you'll also notice
路径的绘制速度决定了粒子的运动方向。你会注意到，
that the paths are not in alignment
这些路径完全不对齐。
whatsoever so again the motion path is
所以，运动路径
just dictating the flow of the particles
只是决定粒子的流动方向，
but where the particles are being
而粒子的
generated is up to the emitter section
生成位置则取决于发射器部分。
so the emitter section and the motion
因此，发射器部分和运动
path are two totally different things
路径是两个完全不同的概念。
but if you want them in alignment all we
如果你想让它们对齐，我们
need to do is align this emitter
只需要将发射器的
position with the starting point of the
位置与
light so right now you can see we've got
光线的起始点对齐即可。现在你可以看到，我们有
some fairly random values but I'll just
一些相当随机的值，但我会把
copy and paste these in here we can
它们复制粘贴到这里。
align these with expressions if you want
如果你愿意，可以用表达式来对齐它们，
but that's just a bit tedious for this
但现在这样做有点繁琐。
there so now I can see that where my
现在我可以看到，我的
starting point is is aligned with where
起始点与
the particular universe is you notice
特定宇宙的位置对齐了。你会注意到
that the particles are stopping
粒子
prematurely and that is because they
过早地停止了，这是因为它们的
just don't have enough lifespan to make
寿命不足以到达样条曲线的
it all the way to the end of that spline
末端。样条
the spline length is at four seconds
曲线的长度现在是四秒，
right now so they were stopping a little
所以它们停得有点
bit short so as they flow along this
短。当它们沿着这条
path there is no more position
路径流动时，由于没有更多的位置
information for it it stops there so
信息，它们就在那里停止了。
that's exactly where the particles stop
这就是粒子停止的位置。 好了，那么
so how is this useful well as the
这有什么用呢？
particles flow along this they have
粒子沿着这条路径流动，它们有
their own velocity we can set these
自己的速度。我们可以把这些
particles to something like a custom
粒子设置成自定义
particle like an arrow in show direction
粒子，比如箭头，并设置方向。这样
we can show a sort of flow along this
我们就能展示粒子沿着这条
path so if I go in here and I set this
路径流动的效果。所以，如果我在这里把它设置
to a sprite colorize and I choose a
为精灵着色，然后
sprite from my
从
particle library let's just use it the
粒子库中选择一个精灵，我们就用
basic arrow and we need to fix a few
基本的箭头吧。
things here we need to make it a little
这里我们需要做一些调整，让它稍微
bit bigger
大一点。
I'll go to the rotation section and set
我进入旋转设置，把
this to orient to motion and rotate the
它设置为“运动方向”，然后把
overall angle of the arrow 90 degrees
箭头的整体角度旋转90度，
because its initial angle is facing up
因为它的初始角度是朝上的，
so we need to point it to the right I
所以我们需要把它指向右边。我
think this is quite a bit of particles
觉得对于我们想要展示的效果来说，粒子数量有点太多了，
for what we're trying to show here so
所以
I'll knock this down to maybe 25
我把它减少到
particles per second and now we can see
每秒25个粒子左右。现在我们可以看到
that we've got particles flowing along
粒子沿着路径流动了。这里有
the path now there's a few quirks to
一些小问题，
this and this is just not exactly a bug
但这并不是一个bug，
it's a matter of working with the math
而是需要顺应数学规律而不是
rather than trying to work against it
试图去对抗它。
when we select that feature right here
当我们选择
which I said is orient to motion keep in
我刚才提到的“运动方向”这个功能时，请
mind at frame 0 there is no motion it
记住…… 在第 0 帧，粒子没有任何运动，它还
has not started moving as of yet so
没有开始移动，所以此时它
there's no motion for it to orient to at
没有运动轨迹可以参考。
that point in time meaning you might be
你可能会
saying well why is that a big deal well
问，这有什么大不了的？
you'll notice as I scrub forward the
你会注意到，当我向前拖动时间轴时，
on that frame 0 where there is no motion
在第 0 帧（粒子没有运动）生成的第一个粒子
is not aligned with the rest of the
与其他粒子没有对齐。
particles now there's a couple different
现在有几种
ways to fix this the easiest fix for
方法可以解决这个问题，最简单的方法
this is to simply keyframe the particles
是直接为每秒粒子数设置关键帧，
per second from 0 to the value that you
从 0 到你
want so if I go back to frame 0 I enable
想要的值。所以，如果我回到第 0 帧，启用
keyframes for particles particles per
粒子关键帧，将每秒粒子数
second set this to 0 and then animate it
设置为 0，然后将其动画设置
to 25 and I scrub forward in time you'll
为 25，再向前拖动时间轴，你会
notice that it essentially skips that
注意到它实际上跳过了
first frame but if I change my particles
第一帧。但是，如果我在
per second here it's now going to
这里更改每秒粒子数，它现在会从第
animate between 25 at frame 1 and then
1 帧的 25 开始动画，一直到
all the way to that change that I made
我
later in time and I don't like that I
后来更改的值。我不喜欢这样，我
don't like having to go back to frame 1
不喜欢每次
every single time I want to make a
想要
change to my particles per second so
更改每秒粒子数时都必须回到第 1 帧。所以还有
there's another way to do this which is
另一种方法…… 这样做是
to use an expression so I can keep my
为了使用表达式，这样我就可以保留
existing value and I can just use an
现有值。我可以用
expression to say if we are at the time
表达式来判断我们是否处于
of the end point of the layer so no
图层的终点时间点。这样，无论
matter where I move this in time if
我把时间线移动到哪里，只要到达终点时间点，就把
we're at that time set the particles per
每秒粒子数设置
second to zero so I'm going to turn off
为零。所以我要关闭
all of my keyframes option or alt-click
所有关键帧选项（或者按住 Alt 键点击
on here and we're just
这里），然后我们
use an if statement that says if
使用一个 if 语句，它的意思是如果某个条件为
something is true do something so if
真，就执行某些操作。如果
something happens and we'll put that in
某个条件为真，我们就把条件放在
here in parentheses if that is true set
括号里，
the particles per second to zero so
然后
that's what we will output if this stuff
输出结果。
in here is true if it's not true then
如果条件不为真，就
output something else now I could say 25
输出其他值。我可以输入 25，这样就
and that would leave it as a fixed value
保持 25 这个固定值。
of 25 or I could just say value and that
或者我可以只输入 value，这样就
will be using the existing value before
使用表达式之前的现有值。
the expression so if something is true
所以，如果某个条件为真，就将
set it to zero else use the existing
其设置为零；否则，使用现有
value so I can say if my current time
值。我可以这样写：如果当前时间
layer so the way we measure time is with
与图层的终点时间点匹配，则输出零，表示我们正处于图层终点时间点的第一帧。我们测量时间的方式是……  “
the word time time as a reserved word
time”这个词被保留
for the current playback time if that is
为当前播放时间。如果它
equal to now it's just a JavaScript
等于“now”，这只是一个 JavaScript 的
thing you have to use two equal signs
规则，你必须使用两个等号，
because one equal sign is used to set to
因为一个等号用于将
something equal to something else two
某个值设置为等于另一个值，而两个
equal signs is to test if something is
等号用于测试某个值是否
equal to something else so if time is
等于另一个值。所以，如果“time”
equal to in point lowercase I capital P
等于小写字母 I 或大写字母 P，则“
end point is equal to the start time of
endpoint”等于图层的开始时间。
the layer so this makes it flexible if I
这样，如果我将
move this layer forward or whatever
图层向前移动，或者进行其他操作，它就非常灵活。
I'm not saying if time is zero because
我没有指定“time”是否为零，因为
if I move this layer forward then while
如果我将图层向前移动，虽然
time isn't a zero here it's actually one
这里的“time”不是零，但实际上是 1
second 25 frames so if I just say the
秒 25 帧。所以，如果我只指定
end point of the layer this will cover
图层的结束时间，就可以涵盖
all of our bases so you notice now that
所有情况。现在你可以看到，
it generally works and I say generally
它通常都能正常工作。我说“通常”，是
because in theory it's still working you
因为理论上它仍然有效，但你
might every now and then run into a one
偶尔可能会遇到一个
little straggler and this honestly I
小小的偏差。说实话，我
don't know the math behind this but if
并不了解这背后的数学原理，但如果
you do see one little straggler like
你看到像这样的小偏差，它
this that isn't quite lining up and I
没有完全对齐，我
can make this a little more obvious by
可以将
setting this to a box and we'll set this
其设置为一个框，使其更明显，我们将它设置
to 0 and 0 in Z and maybe 25 in Y so we
为 0 和 0。  Z 轴方向，Y 轴方向大概 25 个单位，这样我们
can
可以
spread these out just a little bit
稍微分散一下这些粒子。
they're mostly pointing the the right
它们大部分都指向正确的
way but there's sometimes one little
方向，但有时会有一个小小的
crazy particle that is oriented just
粒子方向
slightly the wrong way so if we go into
稍微偏斜。所以，如果我们进入“
emission extras and go into period
发射附加组件”设置，然后进入“
periodicity random which is essentially
周期性随机”设置（这本质上是
a mini randomness control for for the
一个小型随机性控制，用于设置特定
random seed within particular if you set
随机种子），如果将
this to something that isn't a zero this
其设置为非零值，
will snap that one stray a little
就能将那个偏斜的小
particle back into place and this isn't
粒子调整回正确位置。这并非
something that's unique to particular or
特定插件独有的问题，也不是什么
any sort of bug this is just a math kind
bug，这只是
of thing you'll find in after-effects
After Effects 中常见的数学问题。
even using Orient to motion or oriental
即使使用“定向运动”或“定向
long path where you have zero velocity
长路径”功能，当速度为零时，由于
there is no motion to measure at that
没有运动可供测量，所以也会出现这种情况。
work around it so I mentioned being able
因此，你需要想办法解决这个问题。我之前提到过可以
to use something like this as a 3d path
使用 Cinema 4D Lite 将类似这样的效果作为 3D 路径
using cinema 4d Lite so included with
使用。After Effects 中包含一个 Cinema 4D Lite
After Effects is a lite version of
版本。
cinema 4d in fact you can create a new
实际上，你可以直接在 After Effects 中创建一个新的
cinema 4d file right with an After
Cinema 4D 文件，然后
Effects and you can select File max on
选择“文件”&gt;“最大尺寸”&gt;“
cinema 4d file and we'll just call this
Cinema 4D 文件”，我们将其命名为 就像
like cylinder vortex all right now not
圆柱涡流一样，好的。
that I want to turn this into a full-on
我并不是想把它变成一个完整的
lesson about how to use cinema 4d but I
Cinema 4D使用教程，但我
will cover just the basics of what I set
会介绍一下
up in the scene that I was showing you
我刚才展示的场景中的一些基本设置。我会用到这个
so I'm gonna work with the cylinder and
圆柱体，圆柱体内会有气流，
cylinder in fact it's going to flow
实际上它会
around a center object and be and will
围绕中心物体流动，并被
contain it within a larger object so I
包含在一个更大的物体内。这就是
have my internal cylinder right here
我的内部圆柱体，气流会在这里
this is where the error will be flowing
流动，
around or my particles and I'll
或者说我的粒子会在这里流动。我会
duplicate this we'll just make it a copy
复制它，我们把它做成一个副本，然后
of that and I'll make a larger one spy
创建一个更大的圆柱体，就像
dragging this out so I'll put two
拖拽它一样。我会在这里添加两个
different shaders on here so I'll create
不同的着色器。我创建
one shader for the outside let's just
一个用于外部的着色器，我们把它
drop this on there and we'll make this
拖上去，然后把它设置为
slightly transparent go into my
略微透明，进入
transparency and I'll have this mostly
透明度设置，让它几乎
transparent and on the inside will
透明。在内部，我会
create a very plain flat blue texture so
创建一个非常普通的蓝色纹理，所以
I'll apply the another material and
我应用另一个材质，并将
we'll go to its color
其颜色设置为
that too blue
蓝色。
I'm gonna make sure to make a camera for
我会确保为
my scene and we'll look through it by
我的场景创建一个摄像机，然后我们通过它来观察。
clicking on this icon right here I'm
点击这里的图标，我
going to create a null object and we'll
将创建一个空对象，我们将
use this to locate the center of that
用它来定位蓝色物体的中心，
blue object that we want the particles
粒子将围绕这个蓝色物体
to swirl around so I'll go in here and
旋转。所以我在这里
create new null that kind of defaults to
创建一个新的空对象，它默认位于
the center which is right about where I
中心，这差不多就是我
want it but I want to move it down to
想要的位置，但我想要把它移到
the bottom there I'll jump to a
底部。我切换到
different view and make sure I'm kind of
另一个视图，确保它大致位于
aligned near the bottom right there
底部附近。我
and I'm not really gonna animate
不会在
anything within cinema4d I'm just gonna
Cinema 4D 中制作任何动画，我只是要
around these objects all in
在 After Effects 中让粒子围绕这些物体旋转。
after-effects but to prep things to get
但在
into After Effects we need to check a
进入 After Effects 之前，我们需要检查
few things first of all we got to make
一些事项。首先，我们要确保
for video and 800 by 600 I don't think
视频分辨率足够，800x600 的分辨率可能不够，
it's going to cut it so we'll use an HD
所以我们使用
TV 1080
1080x2997 的高清电视分辨率。
I'm going to set this to render all
我将设置为渲染所有
frames
帧，
and we'll make this length maybe 150
并将视频长度设置为 150
frames in length
帧。
now we'll come back to this but there's
我们稍后会回到这里。
do to our objects in here to see our
为了让
null show up in After Effects as a 3d
空对象在 After Effects 中显示为 3D
null we need to apply a certain tag to
空对象，我们需要对这里的对象进行一些特定的操作。我们需要给它添加一个特定的标签，
this and you'll go to tags cinema 4d and
然后进入 Cinema 4D 的标签设置，
select external compositing and this
选择“外部合成”。这样
will tell cinema 4d to take this object
Cinema 4D 就会将这个对象导入到
and have it show up in my After Effects
我的 After Effects
scene I also need to have a separate
场景中。我还需要
alpha channel for this blue object here
为这个蓝色对象创建一个单独的 Alpha 通道，
because I want my particles to interact
因为我希望粒子能够
with it so when we bring this over to
与它交互。所以当我们把这个对象导入
After Effects we're not really bringing
After Effects 时，我们实际上导入的不是几何
over geometry but we're bringing over
体，而是
layers for After Effects to work with so
图层，供 After Effects 使用。
I can define this cylinder here to
我可以把这个圆柱体定义
render as a separate little element with
为一个单独的元素，并赋予它
its own little alpha channel and the way
自己的 Alpha 通道。
we do that is by rendering this single
实现方法是将这个
object to the object buffer and that
对象渲染到对象缓冲区。这听起来
might sound complicated but all we need
可能有点复杂，但其实很简单。只需
to do is go back to that tag section
回到标签设置，
with that cylinder selected and go to
选中这个圆柱体，然后进入
compositing
合成设置。在
at the very last tab of that compositing
合成设置的最后一个选项卡中，
section we have this thing called object
我们会看到一个名为“对象
buffer and I can click on enable and
缓冲区”的选项。点击“启用”，就可以将
this is going to render this object to
这个对象渲染到
object buffer number one all that means
对象缓冲区 1。这意味着要
is going to do a separate pass of the
进行一次单独的渲染。
really all it's doing now it won't do
现在它实际上只处理这张图片的 Alpha 通道，
that unless we enable multi pass
除非我们启用多通道
rendering so I need to go in here and
渲染，否则它不会这样做。所以我需要在这里
select multi pass and I need to click on
选择多通道渲染，然后点击
multi pass and tell it to render both
多通道，并告诉它同时渲染
the RGB image and the object buffer so
RGB 图像和对象缓冲区。这样
it's going to render two different
它就会渲染两个不同的
passes so it's going to render the full
通道，也就是渲染
image of all the stuff that we see and
我们看到的所有内容的完整图像和对象缓冲区。看起来好像很复杂，
lot but it's pretty standard cinema 4d
但这都是 Cinema 4D 的标准操作。
stuff now over here in After Effects I
现在在 After Effects 中，我
already have this file imported because
已经导入了这个文件，因为它是
I created it within After Effects if you
在 After Effects 中创建的。如果你
wanted to import it you can simply go to
想导入它，只需点击“文件”&gt;“
file import so I'll take this drag it on
导入”即可。所以我把它拖到
to a new composition and there we see
一个新的合成中，在那里我们可以看到
our scene if I go in to my sin aware
我们的场景。如果我进入这里的“合成
controls right here I can click on
控制”，我可以点击“
extract and this will get that null
提取”，这将从我的场景中提取
object that I created and the camera
我创建的空对象和摄像机。
if I switch my renderer to a standard
如果我将渲染器切换到标准模式
either draft or full I can add my image
（草稿或完整），我可以添加我的图像
layer so this is the multi pass layers
图层。这就是
that I defined earlier and I need to
我之前定义的多通道图层，我需要
check to find multi passes and this will
勾选“多通道”，这将
just add the two that I have setup in
添加我在 Cinema 4D 中设置的两个图层。
cinema 4d so I'll say add image layers
4D，所以我会添加图像图层，
and now it's showing me my RGB a image
现在它显示了我的 RGB 图像，这
that's the surrender right here and then
就是渲染图，然后是
this object right here this is an
这个对象，这是
isolated and matte of that object so
该对象的隔离遮罩，所以
I'll just turn that off
我把它关掉。
okay so let's create a layer for
好的，我们创建一个图层，
particular apply the effect
应用效果，然后
and I'm going to set up the motion path
设置运动路径。我
so I got my null object right here
这里有一个空对象，
I didn't animate it in cinema 4d I'm
我没有在 Cinema 4D 中制作动画，我
just going to use that null and and it
只是要用这个空对象。它帮了我大忙，
made my life this will be motion path 1
这将是运动路径 1。
and I need to align this to where that
我需要将它与
null is because we've got slightly
空对象对齐，因为
different space here after effects space
After Effects 和
in cinema 4d space don't always line up
Cinema 4D 的空间略有不同，它们并不总是对齐的。在 Cinema
4d where as 0 and 0 is right here in
4D 中，0 和 0 实际上是在这里，而在 After Effects 中，0 和 0 是在这里。
After Effects so my light is probably
所以我的灯光可能在
somewhere off screen but I can simply
屏幕外，但我可以简单地将
align it to that motion path and by
它与运动路径对齐，通过
parenting it and holding the shift key
父级关系并按住 Shift 键，
and that will snap it right to the
它会将其吸附到空对象的
center of that null and then I'll move
中心。然后我将
this light just a little bit off-center
这个灯光稍微偏离中心一点，
so we're gonna have our particles kind
这样我们就有了 我们的粒子从
of start there and swirl upward in this
这里开始，在这个圆柱体中向上旋转。
so this point all I need to do is
所以现在我只需要为
animate my null position and rotation so
我的空物体设置动画，包括位置和旋转。R
R is my null position and Y rotation and
是我的空物体位置，Y 轴是旋转轴。
we'll have this go over four seconds
我们让它持续四秒钟，
we'll have the Y rotation do maybe three
Y 轴旋转大约三圈，然后让它
from the bottom and then all the way up
从底部一直向上移动
to the top so as I scrub through this we
到顶部。当我拖动画面时，我们
should see this light spinning just like
应该能看到这个光点像这样旋转。这就是
so so that is going to be our motion
我们的运动
path so I'll go to particular go to the
路径。现在我转到“特定空间”，找到“
physics error and set this to motion
物理误差”，并将其设置为运动
path number one now if we don't see
路径 1。如果现在还看不到
anything just yet we're not going to
任何东西，
panic
别慌。
remember how we have to align the world
记住，我们需要
a particular to the world in our After
在 After
Effects scene now this gets a little bit
Effects 场景中将“特定空间”与“特定空间”对齐。现在情况变得有点
complicated because we've got particular
复杂，因为我们有“特定
space we've got this light space which
空间”，还有这个光空间，它被
is parented to this 3dnull so where do
这个 3D 空物体作为父级。那么
we get our 3d well we kind of have to
我们从哪里获得 3D 空间呢？我们只能进行
estimate things unless we want to get
估算，除非我们想
into very complicated expressions but
使用非常复杂的表达式。但这
this isn't very difficult to estimate
并不难估算，
the 3d space we need is going to be
我们需要的 3D 空间应该
pretty close to this nulls starting
非常接近。 来到这个空对象的起始
location so let's look at this null
位置，我们来看看这个空对象的
location so it's 0 &amp; 2 60 and 0 so let's
位置，它的坐标是 (0, 2)，也就是 60 和 0，所以我们从
start there so I'll go to emitter set
这里开始。我把发射器设置
this to 0 to 60 and 0 now as we scrub
为 (0, 60, 0)。现在我们
forward we should start to see some
向前拖动，应该可以看到一些
particles rendering let's set this
粒子渲染出来。我们把
velocity to zero these are essentially
速度设置为零，这些粒子基本上是
emitting from the center here and we
从中心发射的，我们
need to move it in its x-axis to be
需要沿着 x 轴移动它，让它到达
where that light was so from here I'm
光源所在的位置。所以从这里开始，我
just going to go into the emitter
进入发射器
position and scoot this over in the
位置，沿着 x 轴移动它，把它放到应该在的位置。
in fact I can go to my different views
实际上，我可以切换到不同的视图，
here I can look at the front view
看看前视图。我们
let's move this around using my camera
用相机
pan tool and it should look like the
平移工具移动一下，粒子应该看起来
particles are centered right around that
正好围绕着那个
spinning null object looks like they
旋转的空对象。看起来它们
should be kind of scooted over just a
应该再稍微移动一下。按 Esc
their temp the escape key to get to our
键切换到上一个
last camera view
相机视图。
so I think we pretty much got all we
我想我们差不多完成了，我们只需要
need to do is define that object buffer
定义我渲染的那个对象缓冲区
that I rendered to knock out the
来消除
particles now this isn't going to be a
粒子。现在这不会是一个……
mask because as you look closely we
遮罩是因为仔细观察，我们
should have particles in the front and
应该看到粒子位于前面，
we should have particles behind it
后面也有粒子。
now I could fake this using an
现在我可以用
observation layer but that is kind of
观察层来模拟这种效果，但这只是权宜之计，
faking it and I want to fake it I want
我想用
to do it the right way so we're gonna
正确的方式来实现。所以我们要
use a different feature here we're gonna
使用不同的功能，也就是
use the Z buffer instead of the
Z 缓冲区，而不是
obscuration layer obscuration layer
遮蔽层。遮蔽层
allows us to obscure particles with
允许我们像使用
After Effects 3d layers like flat layers
平面图层一样，在 After Effects 的 3D 图层中遮蔽粒子。Z
so what the Z buffer is saying is that
缓冲区的作用是指定
there's an object in 3d space where our
3D 空间中存在一个物体，我们的
particles should be obscured and can go
粒子应该被遮蔽在这个物体上，可以位于
behind it and in front of it we define
它的前面和后面。我们
that object in space using black and
用黑白两色来定义这个物体。
white so first I need to define that
首先，我需要定义这个
layer so we'll define the object buffer
图层，所以我们将物体缓冲区定义
as the Z buffer layer and now just
为 Z 缓冲区。现在请
notice it's knocking everything out so I
注意，它遮蔽了所有物体。所以我
need to define where in z space so
需要定义它在 Z 空间中的位置，也就是
essentially the distance from our
从
current camera to where this object is
当前摄像机到这个物体在
in space so what that distance is is
空间中位置的距离。这个距离决定了
what this white value needs to be again
白色值应该是多少。
this is what our object looks like so
这就是物体的样子，
this is white and we need to say in
它是白色的。我们需要指定它在
where in space is this white now we can
空间中的哪个位置是白色的。现在我们可以
do expressions to measure the distance
使用表达式了。 测量
between the camera and this null object
摄像机和这个空对象之间的距离，
right here but really what you're going
但实际上你
to end up doing is just kind of knocking
最终要做的就是不断增加
this value up and up and up until you
这个值，直到
find the particles pop right in front of
粒子正好出现在
the object now in the basic scenes that
对象前面。在我设置的基本场景中，这个值几乎总是
consistently just above 1,000 somewhere
略高于 1000，
on 1200 so if you get it too high all
在 1200 左右。如果值太高，所有
the particles are going to go in front
粒子都会出现在对象前面；如果值
it's too low all the particles would go
太低，所有粒子都会出现在对象后面。
behind it so right around 1200 is
所以，大约 1200 像素的位置
exactly where that object should be in
正是该对象在空间中应该在的位置。这个
space so what this distance is is saying
距离指的是
the distance between the camera which is
摄像机（在
here and where this object is supposed
这里）和该对象在空间中应该在的位置（也就是这个空对象
to be in space which is essentially
所在的位置）之间的距离，
in pixels is 1200 pixels again After
单位是 1200 像素。再次强调，After
Effects is pretty much the only program
Effects 几乎是
that I know that measures units of
我所知的唯一一个以
distance in pixels
像素为单位测量距离的程序。
you know when you
你知道，
to cinema 4d or working with meters or
Cinema 4D 使用的是米、
centimeters or millimeters but After
厘米或毫米，但 After
Effects uses pixels so sometimes you
Effects 使用的是像素。所以有时候你
just have to guess to me
只能靠猜测。
so again we can go in here we can set
我们可以在这里把
this to some sort of custom particle so
它设置为某种自定义粒子。
go to the right colorize will set this
正确的着色方式会将它设置
to our
为我们
nice little arrow basic arrow turn the
漂亮的小箭头，基本箭头，稍微
size up just a little bit we'll set the
放大一点，我们在
rotation here in the rotation section by
这里设置旋转，在旋转部分，将
setting it to orient to motion and set
其设置为“方向到运动”，并将
the rotate to 90 degrees so we want a
旋转角度设置为 90 度，这样我们就需要
little bit of that variation in there so
一点变化，就是这样。
it's not just one single point drawing
不仅仅是绘制一个点，
on so I'll set this to box XYZ
所以我把它设置为 XYZ
individual set X and Z to 0 and we'll
单独框，将 X 和 Z 设置为 0，然后将
set this to I don't know maybe 80 pixels
其设置为大约 80 像素
tall or something like that so now we
高。现在我们可以
see we have got the particles swirling
看到粒子
and moving along that path
沿着路径旋转和移动。这就是它的样子。
like this has a second system with some
这里有一个带有
basic speakers in it just adding a
基本扬声器的第二个系统，只需添加
little bit more of dust or debris in
一些灰尘或碎屑即可。
there was another example that I showed
我在这里展示了另一个
here using a simple pipe like this now
使用类似这样的简单管道的例子。
again I could animate this in After
同样，我可以在 After
Effects but in this case I chose to
Effects 中制作动画，但这次我选择
animate the light right within cinema 4d
直接在 Cinema 4D 中制作灯光动画。我
I said I didn't want to turn this into a
说过我不想把它变成一个
full-on cinema 4d lesson but just to do
完整的 Cinema 4D 课程，只是想
a quick overview in this case I have an
快速概述一下。在这个例子中，我有一个
object that is using a sweep so it's
使用扫描的对象，它
drawing a circle along a spline so I
沿着样条线绘制一个圆。我的样条线在这里，看起来是这样的。我
like that I have a circle that looks
有一个看起来像这样的圆，
like that and then a sweep when I put
然后是一个扫描。当我把这
both of these inside the sweep
两个都放在扫描中时，扫描
essentially draws an object and draws
本质上是
geometry using those two splines taking
使用这两条样条线绘制对象和几何体。以
this spline here I can create a light
这条样条线为例，我可以…… 创建一个灯光，
in use a tag called align to spline and
使用名为“对齐样条线”的标签。
if I animate its position from 0 to 100
如果我将它的位置从 0 动画到 100，
that light will animate along the spline
这个灯光就会沿着样条线移动，
so the geometry and the light will share
几何体和灯光将共享
the exact same spline so this is a good
同一条样条线。这是在 After Effects 中
way to get a motion path right into
创建运动路径的好方法。
After Effects now what you need to do is
现在你需要做的是
pick this tag and actually turn it into
选择这个标签，并将其转换为
keyframes and you'll find that under the
关键帧。你可以在
timeline
时间轴
functions baked objects and then you're
功能中的“烘焙对象”下找到它。然后
going to hit okay right here to take
点击这里的“确定”，将这条样
that spline right here and turn it into
条线转换为
keyframes and it creates a copy and
关键帧，它会创建一个副本。
that's exactly what we're seeing right
这就是我们在
here motion path one copy and this is
这里看到的“运动路径 1 副本”。它
essentially written two keyframes you
实际上写入了两个关键帧。你
can see all the keyframes written over
可以看到所有关键帧都按
time right down here so when I import
时间顺序排列在这里。当我将
that into After Effects I get the motion
其导入 After Effects 时，我会得到一个包含
path light which has all these baked
所有这些烘焙
keyframes and then I can do the same
关键帧的运动路径灯光。然后我可以执行
thing that I just showed you before
之前演示的相同操作，即将其
which is assign this as my motion path
指定为我的运动路径，
and have arrows or whatever travel along
并让箭头或其他元素沿着
the same geometry so those are motion
相同的几何体移动。这些就是运动
paths in general they are pretty fun to
路径。总的来说，它们非常有趣，
if you're working with 3d scenes
如果你正在使用……，绝对值得探索。
imported from other software especially
从其他软件导入的 3D 场景，特别是像
as I showed you right here using cinema
我刚才演示的那样，使用 Cinema
4d lite which is built right into After
4D Lite（它内置于 After
Effects so that is the topic of motion
Effects 中），这就是运动路径的主题。
paths my name is Harry Frank for red
我是 Red Giant 的 Harry Frank，
giant
我们下次再见。
[Music]
[音乐]